### TRINADHA REDDY MALLAVARAM

Web Developer

#### Contact

103,4725,Bourrett Avenue,Montreal,QC H3W 1K9

438-866-2343

reddy.trinadhm50@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/trinadha-reddy-61470678/

https://github.com/trinadh1

https://trinadh1.github.io/trinadh.github.io/

#### **PROFILE**

Programming and web technologies graduate. A Web Developer with Agile scrum methology with more than two years of experience. I am a Quick learner, Creative & organized. I am a startup Enthusiast. I have a stubborn curiosity for how things work.

#### **Technical Skills**

Languages : HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Ruby, PHP, Java, SQL, C/C++

FrameWorks : MVC, Bootstrap, Jquery, ECMAScript6, React. js, Ruby on Rails

**Tools** : Visual Studio Code, Brackets, Eclipse, Sublime.

**Database** : Mysql, SQLite, PostgreSQL,

**Version Control**: Github, Bitbucket, Jenkins

**Web Server** : XAMP, Apache Tomcat

#### **EDUCATION**

**Programming and Web Technologies**, Attestation of College Studies 2019-2021

Institute Superieur d'Informatique- Montreal

Telecommunication, Bachelor of Technology 2010-2014

Srm University- Chennai

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Web Developer

Commutatus, Chennai

Aug 2016 - Feb 2018

- Translate UI Wireframes and Mockups to visual elements of the application
- Built front end of the application in HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, and Jquery.
- Built applications using backend technologies like Ruby on Rails.

- Performed the duty of fixing technical issues related to the designing and programming of websites
- Expertise in MySQL, SQlite3, PostgreSQL
- Experience on Model View Controller (MVC) architecture based Web Applications.

## Web Developer

Code Astra, Hyderabad

March 2015-Sep 2015

- Work with a team of developers to design and create new web sites and Applications
- Develop Web Applications and programming languages such as HTML,CSS,Javascript,Jquery and REST API'S
- Strong understanding of UI, Cross-browser compatibilty

# **PROJECTS**

# Memory Card Game:-

Github link: <a href="https://github.com/trinadh1/MemoryGame">https://github.com/trinadh1/MemoryGame</a>

- In this game, the player has to flip 2 cards each time and memorize its position. In order to win, all the identical cards have to be matched.
- If the two cards are the same number and of same color, it is matched. User wins the game by matching all the cards. The goal is to do it in least number of moves. They are 4 difficulty levels.
- Languages used: HTML,CSS,Javscript

#### ISI Drone:-

Github link: <a href="https://github.com/trinadh1/ISIDrone">https://github.com/trinadh1/ISIDrone</a>

- ISI Drone is an ecommerce website where customers can buy drones by adding items to cart. Admin user can add, modify and delete items sold in the website.
- The admin user can also manage categories, orders and customers through the website.
- Languages used: JAVA, JSP, Servlet, MySQL, Javascript. GIT, BitBucket, Jenkins

## StyleStamp:-

Github link: <a href="https://github.com/trinadh1/StyleStamp">https://github.com/trinadh1/StyleStamp</a>

- Style Stamp is an ecommerce application to sell fashion accessories with a website for admin user to manage products, categories, order and user information.
- Create API's like forgot password, update user profile, change password and filter orders Using CRUD Operations.
- Technologies used: Codelgniter,PHP, Javascript,Jquery,Ajax, Android studio,Java,xamp,MySQL.

#### Image Puzzle :-

Github link: <a href="https://github.com/trinadh1/image">https://github.com/trinadh1/image</a> puzzle

- It's a puzzle game where users are asked to arrange the image to its original position
- Technologies used: HTML5,CSS3,Javscript

Movie Review :- Github Link:

# https://github.com/trinadh1/movie\_reviews

- A movie Application where users can give rating and upload comments to a particular movie
- Technologies used: HTML5,CSS3, Ruby,Ruby on Rails.

# OTHER EXPERIENCE

Delivery Men *Uber Technologies*, Montreal

December 2019-Present

# **REFERENCES**

References available upon request